

ANEESHA B SOMAN

Data scientist

Phone: 8129861194

Address: Marathahalli, Bangalore, Karnataka

Website https://www.linkedin.com/in/aneesha-b-soman-05540968

Email: aneesha161994@gmail.com

Medium articles: https://medium.com/@aneesha161994

Currently working as a Data Scientist in the Research/Product development department of Convergytics Solutions, Bengaluru. Built AI products using regression/classification/cluster models using sklearn, tensorflow, NLP librairies, Computer vision libraries. Built products related to Market analytics, NLP and Computer Vision. Experience in working closely with the frontend team for integration of various features of the AI product, and also with the DevOps for the deployment of the AI product. Highly skilled in python, SQL and Azure. Overall 4 years in the IT industry. Been in the Data Science Field for 3 years which includes 1 and half years of Industry experience and the rest is Teaching Experience as a Trainer for Data Science. Prior to it worked as a Javascript Web developer.

Skill used Projects on the projects:

1.Python, Pandas, Numpy,

2.SQL(Postgres DB) and SQLAlchemy

3.Linux

4. Azure and AWS

5. Selenium and Beautiful Soup

6.Deep learning(Tensor flow)

7.NLP- embeddings, Adobe services Api,NLTK , transformers,regex, and Unsupervised learning models

8. Document conversions

9. Market analytics-Sklearn, Price elasticity, Conjoint analysis, Multinomial Logit models, Regression 10. personal projects on sales and marketing: Time series, clustering, Bayesian Methods, Tree-based learners, SVM, XGBoost, and Random Forest.

11. All projects needed Docker, Azure Vnets, Fast Api and Github

March 2022-present

February 2022-present

12. Research(papers and articles)

13.Computer vision- opency, Yolo

EXPERIENCE

Convergytics Solutions

Data Scientist

Worked in the R&D department to develop various AI products:

- 1. NLP Project: Contract Reader AI Reader
- 2. Pricing Optimisation Project
- 3.OCR Projects

PaperPedia

Data Scientist Researcher

Research papers on various Machine learning models using python, statistics and Macro Economics

Fliprobo

Data Scientist May 2021 -Dec 2021

Scrapping data using selenium from various websites to build regression and classification models and predict Social media comments nature, cars prices, flights prices, real estate prices etc. and also show the relationships of feature to feature and label to feature using visualization techniques. Also building Image classification models. Preparing PPT and document to be presented to the customer

Whitehat Jr

Tutor Professional

September 2020-August 2021

Teaching Data Science and JavaScript through various IDEs and editors. Students were taught to scrape data using selenium and build regression and classification models.

Projects that were taught to the students were sentiment analyzer, temperature prediction model building and web scrapping. Promoted into Mentorship role in the Organization in a short span of time.

B-On optimized business solutions private limited Junior Web developer

June 2019-July 2020

Website development and maintenance of various companies

UPSC Tutor

June 2017-June 2019 Freelancer

Taught History, Geography, Economics and Environment in various reputed UPSC institutes. The students were taught with PPT and given PDF content to refer.

SKILLS -

- In depth understanding of Machine learning Algorithms
- Statistics
- 3. Deep learning
- 4. Python
- 5. Javascript and NodeJS
- 6. Web scraping: Selenium and Beautiful soup
- 7. SQL: Querying, PostgresDB
- Visualizations of datasets: Matplotlib, plotly
- Web development: HTML and CSS 9.
- 10. Excellent PPT and PDF presentation and communication skills
- 11. Docker
- 12. Computer Vision: Tensor Flow

- 13. Natural Language Processing: Genism, Spacy, NLTK, Bert, Hugging face, sklearn
- 14. Linux
- 15. Microsoft Azure
- 16. Team player, team building, and leadership qualities
- 17. FastApi and Rest API
- 18. Github
- 19. OCR: Tesseract, Google API, Azure API
- 20. Beautifulsoup and Selenium
- 21. Economics in Pricing Strategy
- 22. Quick Learner
- 23. ML Unit Testing
- 24. Linear Programming

EDUCATION —

IGNOU	PG Diploma in Statistics	Jan 2022- Present	
Data trained, Bangalore	PG Diploma in Data Science((NLP with ML, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Business Analytics with Tableau)	May 2021- December 2021	
SRM University, Chennai	Information and Telecommunication, Bachelor of Technology	2012-2016	with First class (7.67 CGPA)
Christ Nagar ISC School	ISC	2011-2012	First class with 84%
Christ Nagar ICSE School, Trivandrum	ICSE	2010	First class with 83%

CERTIFICATIONS =



Cost and Economics in Pricing Strategy



Cost and Economics in Pricing Strategy



Market and Competition in Pricing Strategy



IBM Data Science Professional Certificate



Hackers Rank Certification

JavaScript



Linux Mastery

LinkedIn Assessment Python

LinkedIn Assessment SQL

LinkedIn Assessment Machine Learning

LinkedIn Assessment Linux

Forecasting models and time series business models in Python under Diogo Alves de Resende(Udemy)

Google Cloud Platform Big Data and ML training certificate

Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Scientist Associate udemy course

Algorithms-Divide and Conquer, Sorting, Searching, and Randomized Algorithms(Stanford University)

Data Structures, Graphs, and Shortest Path

VOLUNTEERING 2020

1.Started an NGO Teach Digital for India (Women literacy)

Selected a few BPL women from different parts of India and gave them training for UPSC exam

2. Hospital Visits in SRM Medical Hospital (Sick)

2014

3. Part of Rotary activities (Tsunami Affected students)

2008

Part of various camps, which was attended during my childhood, supporting Tsunami affected children who were rehabilitated and been sheltered in National Tennis Academy, Pataudi, Gurgaon for studies and Tennis.

HONORS 2012-2016

Class representative

SRM University

Handled all the responsibilities including Attendance, file keeping, distribution of assignment copies, coordination between teachers and students.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Tennis | Gurgaon

Pre-Quarter finalist in Asian Junior Lawn tennis championship

Athletics | Thiruvananthapuram
GOLD MEDALIST in 400m Athletics
GOLD MEDALIST in 800m athletics
GOLD MEDALIST in shotput and discuss throw

Music and Dance

- 1. GOLD MEDALIST in English solo music
- 2. Performed a music gig at ATLAS FILM AWARD FUNCTION3. played the guitar at various musical performances
- 4.youtube music channel with more than 700 views
- 5.SILVER MEDALIST in interhouse dance competition

Content creation

Telegram channel with 5000 followers

https://t.me/upsc daily CA

WEBSITES

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aneesha-b-soman-05540968

GitHub: https://github.com/aneeshabsoman123

YouTube Music covers: https://www.youtube.com/user/aneesha123able

Poems: https://www.instagram.com/unearthing_life/

HOBBIES

1.tennis 3.dance 5.poetry

2.music 4. pencil sketching

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth-01/06/1994 Nationality-Indian Marital status: Single

LANGUAGES

English (read, write and speak) Hindi (read, write and speak) Malayalam (speak)